Good morning. How's it going?
Hey, good morning. Good.
And if I ask you a quick question.
Of course, go ahead.
So.
I really,
I gained a lot of insight as to kind of
have proceed from this class.
So it's been great so far,
but one thing I'm a little unclear on is
the starting point of the the copilot
instruction files and the starting point
of all those markdown files and.
How to flesh them out?
As thoroughly as.
I would like to right and.
I guess that's the question. You know,
when we started out,
we we went pretty quick, you know, um.
Did you start out with just a basic
skeleton of copilot instructions and then
build on that moving forward from there?
Did we?
Does that make sense what I'm asking?
Yeah, right. I mean,
I think this is a challenge with with any
new technology is knowing where to,
where to begin, right. And you know,
Right.
in my, in my experience it was, you know,
you kind of, you know,
figure it out as you go along.
But you know,
I think we're going to actually touch on
Right.
this this morning a bit because we're
working in Greenfield,
which means that we are in a going to be
starting from scratch, so.
So, so, so in a sense,
we're gonna have to do a lot of what
OK, cool.
we're what you're gonna need to do and
let's if you were gonna bring this into a
new project, but just to give you a,
you know, a sense of it.
If you're going to start field
examination,
you you want to establish those
instructions and starting with the.
I tell you how to build other
instructions and other other files, right?
Mhm.
Because then as you go and do your,
you know your exploration into your code
Mhm.
base,
you're going to want to be able to create,
you know, different.
Different instructions for different
technologies and and just kind of build
that up as you're starting to understand
that that that code base.
So that's you know that's kind of I think
the the beginning is where you.
Establish those, those,
those core instruction files,
prompt files,
and because prompt files are like,
you know, they're task oriented,
they're they're ready to get things done.
So you kind of.
Risk as you're finding tasks that you
want to execute that you want to be able
to do more than, you know,
just the one offs and then you capture
those into prompt files, right?
And then we're gonna get into.
Right.
The chat mode files today so that we
understand kind of how to tie those
instructions and those those prom files
into a higher level persona that we can
actually leverage and and have that have
a an understanding of the a better
understanding of the work that we're
asking it to do.
But you know it's it's so that's.
So I think you know the instruction files
are key to guidance and they're in terms
of for for the A I to understand what the
context is that you're trying to
accomplish, right.
And that's really what you that's what
you want to to build up and then you can
Yep, you have it.
get into some of the more sophisticated
things.
Cool.
Sure.
John, good day. Yeah, this is Boris.
Good day. Good afternoon.
Yeah.
Today.
I would like to ask something about the
about the procedure not related to the
course content itself.
I need to get a voice document for the
payment that I made. Who can help me?
I wrote that request to court support
team and didn't get any answer.
Maybe you know.
All right,
you should have got a a message from Eric
Ruffras.
Yeah, I wrote him to today.
He didn't respond me.
Maybe it's too early for him. I will wait.
All right, well, I I'll,
I'll make a note to contact something.
Yeah, if you can help me or remind him,
that will be good.
And you're looking you're looking for an
invoice,
is that what I'm saying or some sort of?
Yeah, I need an official invoice,
you know, for my payment.
All right. All right.
I'll make a note of that. You're welcome.
Thank you, John.
Anything else from anyone?
No, no, all the rest is is good. Yeah,
working with your examples.
Oh.
All right, give me one second.
Just I I need to finish up one thing here
so I can show you.
Something I learned.
All right,
just I'll just need one more minute.
Thanks.
All right, I'm ready to go. So today.
Let me share my screen.
And let me start the presentation.
OK, so this is the the Greenfield part.
So we're in this exercise or this could
in the next two days.
What I want to try to to take us through
is that that that Greenfield exercise
where we're going to start essentially
from an idea and then we're going to try
to.
Move that idea all the way through into
an implementation. So in this.
In this what we're going to talk about
today is and you know start off with a
discussion of MCP servers and then I want
to get into custom agents and what and
then something called what I'm referring
to is an AI assisted workflow which is.
A method that I'm using that you know
starts with requirements and moves us all
the way through into an implementation.
So we kind of break it down into steps
that we can execute that that will
basically encapsulate those those those
requirements into something that actually.
It becomes something that can be turned
into code.
So we'll talk about project requirements,
what those requirements are.
I want to go into a I want to show you a
conceptual model that I'm using to build
an application with and talk about to
some how to deal with.
Both the structural rules or structural
business rules as well as the processes
that go into an application and how to
capture that in such a way we can use it
to to help us with the A I generation.
We'll we'll talk about project
instructions.
And then implementation prompts which are
which are basically the the the guiding
the the guides that to tell that that
tells the AI you know how to build the
different parts of the application that
we want and then we'll go through some.
Lessons learned so.
Let's, uh, get started with this.
So first I wanted to talk a bit about
copiloted instruction files and because
we have, you know,
we talked about how to manage the context
window and how that every instruction
file that we load or that we define gets
loaded into our context and that we want
to have a finer level.
Control over how that works.
So I just wanted to give you some tips
about or some techniques and how you can
do that. So as we've discussed,
every copilot prompt includes a relevant
instruction file automatically.
But you you can use a you can use a a
clause in your instruction file which is
the apply to clause that can specify a
specific file extensions that this.
Instruction file is intended to to
provide guidance to and here we can see
that we're specifying, you know,
TypeScript, JavaScript and Python files.
In the apply to clause,
and what this will do is essentially 2
things.
One is that if you're working within one
of these files without extension,
then those instruction files are
available to you and you can actually use
them.
They'll automatically be included in the
prompts that you submit.
And the other thing is that if you're
working in a file that is not one of
these extensions.
This instruction file will not be
included in your context,
so it gives you the ability from a file
extension point of view to actually
control which instruction files are
included in your context.
And you can do this again with with
different levels of scope.
You can you can.
The first example here is global,
it applies to everything and the second
one is directory specific where it is
applying to all the files in a particular
folder. So you can have.
Uh, instruction files.
That only like to that folder and then
you here we have the type specific or the
extension specific specific files as well.
But if we talk about what profiles they
they they don't control.
Profiles execute tasks,
they don't control instructions.
And I just want I want to make another
point about the the applies to.
There are other things that you can.
Specify in the applies to as well.
I'll I'll try to point that out a bit
later, but it's not.
It can be more than just just just like a
file extension.
For example if you're working with an
organization wide.
Instruction file you can specify in an
instruction file and it applies to a
specific repository,
and there's other flavors of these
patterns for applies to that you can
leverage to restrict which instruction
files are actually included.
So profiles execute tasks.
They don't control instruction inclusion.
So you can't say in a prompt file that
you want to have to utilize a particular
instruction file.
So you can't you can reference
instruction file requirements in the
context.
You don't specify,
which means what you could put in
requirements within that in that prompt
file, but it doesn't. You don't.
You can't use it to actually auto include,
right?
And then the instruction files that
you're you have in your file are.
Use the applies to to Matt.
It still determines whether in its
inclusion chat modes are personas not not
pattern controls.
Like you basically use chat modes to
create specialized context and then you
then you can route those.
Chat modes can include instructions
itself and sure if you can so you can,
but not references to other instruction
files.
So here you have the interaction model,
the files being edited.
It looks to apply to to see if there's a
match.
If there's a match then it auto includes
instructions, otherwise it it adds.
The the chat mode persona and then it
generates a response. If it doesn't match,
then it just skips that particular set of
instructions and then moves on to the
chat mode persona. So there's a yes.
Shut down.
Just a quick question around prompts and
instructions.
Are you able to get one of those?
I I guess instructions would be it to run
a particular script if you had a script
file in one of your folders in that code
space.
That would be more something that you
would try to do with a a prompt file,
because prompt files are intended to try
to do something right.
Oh.
OK. Yep. Yeah.
Right. And you know, I haven't.
I haven't actually tried what you're
suggesting,
but I don't have any reason to think that
it would work.
OK, OK. Yeah, no,
I just it's something that I've
experienced with another A I coding
product that you create skills and skills
Bye.
can you put your scripts in there and
they can reference and run those scripts,
say like get a local pipeline or whatnot.
Right. Well,
actually a couple pilot support skills
now too,
as of I think the beginning of the month.
OK.
So you so you can create a skills folder
and and and put skills like that and it
should match the standards.
So it's whatever skills that you're using
in you know cloud code or whereabouts
that you're you're working.
They should they should work here as well.
Thanks.
Yeah, right. I haven't,
I haven't had time to work with those.
So I would encourage you to kind of
investigate them on your own.
So here's the control hierarchy.
It basically starts with the the context
of the current file that's being edited.
Then it apply uses the applied to pattern
to determine which instruction files to
include in the context.
It then brings in any active chat mode
that you're using and adds that persona
to the context.
If you're running a prompt file then it
will. If it has,
if it references any additional
instructions in the prompt file,
you can then leverage those in and then
you can use manual at mentions which are
references to other tools that.
Which are explicit instruction reference
that you can bring in.
To the hierarchy.
So here's some practical control
strategies for approaches to managing
that in that content.
You have those specific patterns with the
domain specific guidance. So for example,
we're specifying this.
An applies to for the TS files for
instance.
If you if there's no apply to then it's
only manual inclusion only in the docs
that need to be to be explicit opt in.
Then we have global overrides like the
base plus the specialized where you can
do you know.
Things like I want to include all the
files and then directory isolation so you
can use project sections like like
folders as I mentioned to actually
include context.
So here's some other examples of.
Using that apply to,
so it's AI assisted output instructions.
We're applying saying that this
particular applies everywhere,
so it's a fundamental providence
requirements,
but you might have a vertical slice
implementation instructions that only
apply to code.
And and that so that was only code files
only.
And then we talked about using a a a
specific directory or a specific file
extension.
So applies to a field control automatic
inclusion via these glob patterns,
prompt files, reference,
but don't control instruction selections.
And the chat modes and the personas add
personas but not pattern overrides.
And this hierarchy of file instructions,
persona,
task and manual are the order in which
they are actually evaluated in terms of
bringing them into the context.
So you wanna be intentional with patterns
to optimize that content and that's
specific specificity is your friend and
pattern match patterns that actually use
cases. Yeah buddy.
As do you do you have like any
documentation links on like like for
because like the apply to I'm sure
there's other other key like you know
like properties or something.
Do you do you have the links to those
documentation available?
I I don't have them in the in the deck,
but I'll I'll get them up in the chat.
OK. Yeah, that'd be cool. Thanks.
Yeah.
So now let's move and talk just a brief
bit about MCP servers.
So this is a way of of adding additional
functionality into into copilot.
It stands for a model context protocol.
It's basically a protocol that allows
agents to exchange information.
With each other and with the the copilot
tool,
so it allows you to connect to actual
data sources.
There are pre-built servers that provide
ready to use capabilities,
which is probably the.
Big use case for these is you've got a,
you know,
let's say a good example is that you do a
lot of work with Terraform for instance,
and instead of building an instruction
file for Terraform,
you could actually just just add an
extension.
For an MCP server for Terraform and then
that would allow you to bring in all of
the the capabilities that they've built
into that MCP server, which could be,
you know,
guidance for like Intellisense in context
completion.
Well as guidance for you know different
activities or actions that you can
perform with that MCP implementation of
of of a Terraform server so you can
configure any servers.
Not build them is not exactly.
It's not you can build them.
They're actually fairly easy to actually
to build. So if you have.
Uh, with a custom.
Um.
If you have some sort of custom data
source that you want to make available to
your to your prompts,
you can actually build a server for that.
And there's many community servers
available for common things like I was
mentioning Terraform and the like.
So built in just a peek into the
architecture.
The key components are the client,
which is our Visual Studio code,
and you can configure this by saying
which which which MCP servers you want to
make available to you.
Then there's the server which is the
pre-built tools.
We install those by installing extensions.
And then there are the resources which is
on the back end with that server accesses.
So the idea is VSVS code copilot client
uses Jason and RPC to talk to an MCP
service transport layer and then that MCP
protocol.
But then I need protocol.
Then these are different protocols that
talk to different resource types like
APIs, databases, et cetera.
So so these are the things that that they
can do.
As I mentioned you can do context to work
completions which is access to projects
which has access to project specific
content. You can invoke tools via via MCP,
you can you can provide a.
Per project guidance in terms of custom
instructions and then also security
boundaries.
That's where you can have controlled
access to resources.
And then popular MCPMCP servers are
things that will access things like
Github repos, database systems,
file systems, web APIs,
all all these types of things you can
find MCP servers to to support.
And if we search for MCP in Visual Studio
code extensions,
it'll bring up other ones that are
available to install from the.
Visual Studio Gallery and there's also a
public registry of MCP servers at the
Model Context protocol dot IO site.
So take a look at that real quickly.
I want a different. No, that's fine.
So we go to the extension tab in Visual
Studio Code.
If we type in MCP then this will list all
of the MCP tools that are that we that
are available to you that you can install.
You can scroll through those or you can
say I want I want interested in one that.
Has something to do with terraform.
And then you will see here we have a a
Terraform extension for MCP that has 101.
6 million downloads.
So it's a very popular MCP, yeah.
You you're not sharing your screen if
you're if you're trying.
Can we see your slides still?
Oh, I'm sorry, that's my mistake. Yeah,
so you what I did was go and do some MCP
sort of MCP search for MCP in Terraform
and it showed up here at Terraform.
Extension. That's very popular.
Buddy had a question.
Oh,
that was just about sharing your screen.
Yeah. Thank you.
Alright, so it's like highlighting.
So,
so this is basically what you the way
that I would I treat is that there's
something that or some sort of technology
that I'm using that isn't intrinsically
supported by.
By GitHub Copilot,
then this is a great way to bring in some
expertise into into into your context
that would allow you to take advantage of.
Of different capabilities.
If we hit the we go down to the chat
window.
You can you can see also a list of those
tools.
You can see that what the what commands
that that that they they support that you
can take advantage of.
So for example you can search using this.
This tool here the Visual Studio code
insert documentation and you can actually
ask questions of Visual Studio code and
here we can determine of the of the MCP
servers that we are currently.
Have currently installed which of those
are actually currently active and as
Philip mentioned in the course,
we can actually create the tool sets here
that will allow us to invoke individual
tool sets that have you know those
particular capabilities are.
Relevant to the current work that we're
actually trying to do. Buddy, anything?
I was. I'm sorry. I didn't mean to.
So.
Yeah, no worries.
Yeah, I have a question.
So this is just a chat window that you
connected to an MCP server.
I'm a little confused I think 'cause
maybe you didn't have to share your
screen initially like.
Yeah,
basically the idea is that you can
install an MCP server through the
extensions marketplace,
then that's become a tool that you have
available here that you can take
advantage of for example.
You know the VS code server.
We have some of these which are built in
right that are that you all have
available that you don't have to install
and you can choose whether you want to
configure them or not and then you have.
Tools that you might that you can install
that will show up here and you can see,
for example, there's a mermaid,
a mermaid tool,
and then you can then drill down into
that tool and specify specific things
that that tool can do that you're
interested in taking advantage of.
And every single check box here adds up
to our invent or our quota of.
Right now it's like 128 that we can have
installed and and turned off and turned
out in the.
In copilot so that we can take advantage
of them.
So those are MCP server that when you go
to configure tools that some of them are
Yeah.
MCP or?
Right, right. So if we went in here,
we say we want to install the Hashi Corp
Terraform installation.
It'll since this is not Microsoft tool,
it's make you see it's basically telling
you if you you trust to to install that.
So we should we see that it's now
installed.
If we go to tools.
Mm.
Let's see if it shows up here.
Was that MCP server you installed or is
it just like a non?
I don't know. Yeah,
maybe it's not an MCP server.
Yeah, it doesn't look like it is.
How about this one?
This looks like it's the same thing.
No, this one, yes.
So that's installed.
John,
I'm just wondering if you have any
experience with Playwright,
the browser connection with AI.
No.
Um,
you have some experience with it and and
um.
Use it to generate some tests that for
and type testing.
That seems to work pretty well.
Yeah, OK. Yeah,
that's that's the context I was thinking
about it in with testing.
Right, right.
So you can you know you could add that in
as an instruction for maybe test
instructions that and you know end to end
testing should be should be implemented
using playwright and it'll go about the.
Adding that to your your your tool set
and include that in your in right in my
test using that using that tool.
Alright, so this is not exactly doing.
What I thought. So I'll look into this,
see what I'm doing wrong here.
I don't take a heavy use of them.
I'm finding that most of what I need to
do right now is part of the built in
tools because I spend a good amount of
time right now building out instruction
files, prompt files and chat rooms.
So let's go back to the slides.
And and talk a bit about the custom
agents.
But these are specialized A I assistance
with tailored expertise for specific
development tasks that you can configure
tools and capabilities.
You can provide a custom instructions for
defining behavior.
You can create reusable approach which
allows us to create.
Reusable profiles across projects and
it's available in multiple environments.
So many different environments support
these custom agents.
Now there's been a change in.
And and GitHub copilot is moving away
from the concept of a chat mode into a
more a more robust concept of a a a
custom agent.
And so in just in the the January release
they they changed to where.
Agents are can be located.
They they used they used to be required
to be in a in a GitHub copilot chat under
score modes folder and they had a a
structure to them.
But but now custom agents are are stored
in the Copilot agents folder and they're
they're markdown files now.
So everything in Copilot will be a
markdown file.
And they're basically the idea they're
gonna be building out the the schema for
the the the the agents to add more and
more capabilities to make these agents
more and more robust and more capable.
So these all work,
these agents work in different ID ES.
So if we go to to creating a GitHub,
we can actually go in in into GitHub and
we can walk through to the create a
custom agent there.
And you can configure it and then you can
actually commit it there,
but we can also do this in.
In a visual in Visual Studio,
so for example.
If we, uh, let's close all these.
And I if I go down here to the agents tab.
One of the things I can do is I can
specify to create to configure a custom
agent and it will bring a list of the
agents that it that we that it we want to
potentially edit or we can create a
custom agent so that.
That why asking it to create a new one
and notice that it there's two places
that we can store in the GitHub agents
folder and in user data.
I I haven't mentioned this up to this
point,
but there's also a place that you can
store.
Um.
Custom agents and instructions in your
user data folder and those don't get
committed into the repository.
Those are just available to you,
but they're available across all of your
projects that you might be working on.
So in some cases it's it's useful to
store.
Things that might be specific to the way
that you work as opposed to other other
other people and you can keep those those
user specific instructions in a in a
place that you have where you can access
them but they're not part of the
repository.
But normally they would go into the
executives agent folder.
We'd give it a name would be my agent.
For instance and it will create the the
shell of what that of an agent that you
can start with.
You can see that you have to if you get a
name and give it a description,
you can give it a list of arguments that
so that you the the you can actually.
Pass information into the agent and
actually have it to respond to that and
then you can define specifically what
that custom agent does,
including its behaviors capabilities.
Let me show you an example that I created.
Go to the configure and I created one
called test agent here.
I I wanted an agent that I could just
verify that it was actually showing up in
the UI correctly as well as it allows you
to perform.
Function.
So here this one has a a hello command
that basically does a hello world and
gives you a response back.
So you can invoke that by saying.
At I wanna use the test.
Agent.
And say hello, there's the commands.
And but I didn't do that right?
It's uh at.
Let's stop this.
And you can see that it it's returned
that text that we asked it to to include.
So if we look at this the file that's
basically it's telling you that this is a
test agent,
that you're a test agent designed to help
verify that VS code agent functionality
respond to simple command.
To demonstrate those those agent
capabilities.
So that first one I was hello you can say
slash info and then you can pass it a a a
file name.
There is the argument list the argument
hints of what which you can pass.
He's also here a list of the of the tools
that the the agent is able to access.
You can restrict what it you know what it
has access to and what it can able to do.
Here is a account filing the accounts
lines in our file.
Here we have a a list which will list.
So these are the capabilities and the of
this of this test agent.
Some behaviors as always confirmed the
command.
The command received before executing,
but like their responses, etcetera.
So you're defining how it should behave.
You can also you can also define up here
in the metadata.
Prom files that you want to have the
agent have access to so that it can
execute individual prompts and then you
can create commands in the in the chat
agent that will actually execute those
prompts so that way.
You don't have to, you know,
manually execute prompts.
You can actually execute prompts within
the context of the chat mode and any
additional instructions or guidance that
are that's in the chat mode will then be
part of the context.
And this again allows you to more fine
tune the AI so that it's actually.
You know,
and so it's actually that prompt is
actually getting in a larger context or a
better context than that you're doing
doing it individually.
John,
really what you're doing by doing this is
you're just creating canned,
canned commands that you want to use,
right? Assigning them.
Yeah,
but that's part of what you what we're
doing here, right? We're.
What we're we're defining the commands,
which are the,
there's two different kinds of commands,
simple commands like these which just do
basically, excuse me,
basic simple instructions like the.
Info here provides information about
specific files which is location and
basic content summary.
And the response to read the file
provided 2 to three sentence summary of
the contents of that file, right?
So this is the prompt effectively that's
being executed in response to the this
particular command.
That's also says you for a more
complicated task for things that require
multiple steps and.
More definition.
That's where a prompt file would come in.
So you can now then have the chat mode
call out and have a command that calls
out to that prompt file and and has it do
something on on your behalf and.
In addition to that,
you have the ability to find these
behaviors,
so you can fine tune that persona to have
a a specific approach using specific
things.
You can also define the the skills that
it it's capable of doing. So let me.
Take a Let's look at a more sophisticated
one. Let's look at a security reviewer.
And so here we see a name and we got the
description.
We have some data that was put from our
AI prominence.
Um.
Here is the prompt that created it,
et cetera.
And here we see what some core expertise
is, what the methods that it uses,
the output format that it's actually
trying to achieve. So there's.
You know, different expertise.
So these are still building these without
adding additional commands and
capabilities.
But at first at first glance what it does
is it defines the it defines the
essentially the core expert,
the core expertise that that particular.
Chat mode has and and it's behavior that
that you want to have it support alright.
Any questions on these are?
Um.
Had a question. So did you? Oh, go ahead.
OK.
Tom, uh, raise your hand.
Hello.
OK, yeah,
so did you have to create all these
agents yourself or are there any pre
canned ones that are built in?
There are some pre.
There are some pre canned ones.
Uh, what's my here? It's uh.
Here is the AI agent expert.
The data analysis expert are both
pre-canned ones that you have that are
built in.
OK. Thanks.
Then the rest of them I built by just
saying I want to create a chat mode for
this particular persona and that's how
these were built and and and still
working.
I have an instruction file for chat notes
that kind of built that helped me build
these out.
Dan.
Yeah.
Are you gonna are these gonna be provided?
Because I'm looking in that repo,
the AI assisted software development.
I don't see agents there.
Yeah, yeah, I haven't pushed.
These are obviously headlines.
Oh.
OK.
Buddy.
Yeah,
I found you probably might know this,
but there's like a repo code
Austincopilot. I'll send a link,
but it's like a a shared community repo
that it it's kind of similar to a repo
that you have where it's got like a.
Share like agent instructions and agents
and stuff like that. I thought.
I thought it was pretty cool.
I I just wanted to share in case.
It's a awesome copilot, she said.
Yeah,
I also I also put the link in in the uh
in our chat too.
Mm.
Yeah, awesome. Cool.
It looked pretty cool.
It had a lot of a lot of agents and
instruction files, prompt files,
and I think they even had a skills. Yeah,
they have a skills folder too.
I don't think there's any skills in there
though yet.
I.
Oh no, there's a lot of skills.
Yes.
But I I was just sharing I I I had found
that uh yesterday.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I heard that I I see it mentioned before
and I and.
So you can see here.
Yeah, like if you look at the top one,
was it the the.net upgrade?
That was a pretty good one where it was
kind of it kind of sets up like an agent
for I guess if you wanna if you have a
lot of projects you need to upgrade.
Uh, in.net.
Right.
Right. That's a great site.
And the idea is that this also gives you
guidance for the how they how you how can
build these yourselves for your own
purposes, right.
Or or you can adopt these and bring those
I was I I was just copying them in just
kinda like how your repo like where
in. So it's.
Right.
they're like you you could copy them
modify them you know to suit your needs
but like it seems like like they're
they're just shared you know like you
know like I guess community shared.
Uh, ones that uh,
I guess they don't work exactly the way
you want. You just modify them, right?
Right.
So these are props. Um.
It.
I just want to share.
I don't know how good they are not.
They just they look like another resource.
Yeah, yeah. Well,
thanks for pointing it out.
And I think that's also a worthwhile
place to to look for things that have
already built that you don't have to.
Try to build yourself.
So and you can see here there's, you know,
there's a number of instruction files for
specific technologies that you could then
leverage,
or at least they're used as a basis for
starting out something that's.
Yeah, tell us what you're trying to do.
So, so yeah, so this is a good resource.
Thanks for pointing that out.
OK, uh.
So we went through this process with the
agent.
Um.
So then in Visual Studio Code I show we
are going to open up the Copilot chat and
do the agents drop down to create a new
and I showed you how to create a new
custom agent using the using those props
where you can specify the location.
And then put a name of the agent in it
will configure this as a dot agent dot MD
file and then you can use a configure
tool for that tool selection.
Uh.
And then you you can set the model
property for to to to determine what
specific AI model preference that you
have for actually to run that when you
run that that custom agent.
So that will so you can basically say I
want to run this agent when you run this
particular.
Agent you always want to use you know
ChatGPT or or Claude's sonnet or whatever
model that you you choose.
This is a little hard to read.
So this is we talk about the name,
the description,
the tools that are allowed the model.
Here we see Chapter GB4 Tour the target
would be optional VS Code or GitHub
copilot which which you're you're you're
talking targeting that to be executed.
And compete key components are some YAML
front matter with some metadata,
which is what we're looking at here,
and then the markdown content below.
So here's a test specialist one and we
here we're looking at the the basic that
we we want to be able to what essentially
what the the name is in the description
and then here is the actual instructions
that we want to be or the.
The persona that we're trying to build
and what the capabilities are for that
particular chat mode or or agents.
Here's another example.
We're an implementation planner, right?
You can analyze requirements,
create detailed technical specifications,
always structure plans with clear
headings. So this is basically.
So the idea here is that this here we see
guidance for these are additional
instructions that we've added into the
agent over and above what the
instructions would be in any instruction
file that would apply to this particular
chat.
So using them on github.
com you can use the agents panel tab to
define those agents in in the IDE we use
that select agent to.
To select which agents that we want to to
to to be utilizing and in the the GitHub
Copilot CLI you can use the slash agent
command to select an agent.
And and execute a command line argument
for that agent to execute.
So that's the best practices.
So start simple.
Create one agent for a specific pain
point.
Responsibilities restrict to the tools to
enable only the tools that the agent
actually needs.
Refine those instructions based on the
the real usage and then you can create or
enterprise agents for common tasks.
Include use examples in the agent
description and then validate that
behavior before you roll it out to to
using in production.
Any questions so far on these agents?
There was the actions or I I can't
remember where it was like edit, search,
read and stuff like is that.
Yeah, those, yeah, those,
those are the tools then, right.
The tools, yes, yeah.
Those are the.
So they're basically they're restricting
what that agent or that agent can do.
So like like say like the planner,
you know there's that planner one now I
guess that that one that's built and that
there's the planner I guess.
I guess that's how they control it from
not editing or something like that I
guess like if you wanted to make your own.
Right.
Custom planner agent. Um,
you could you could restrict it that way.
Yeah, that's what we're looking at.
I think here is the a planner
Yeah, yeah.
implementation.
It does the tools that that is available
is that I can read, search and edit.
How do you how do you know what what's
what the available tools are?
Is it the same tools that are whenever
you pull down the tools in in in the UI
you know you could pull the you could
click on the tools.
Is it the same ones?
You're referring to these tools here?
Yeah, yeah.
If we look at the built in here,
we have edit, we have read,
we have to search, so yeah.
So yeah,
so you could kind of like that's I guess
that's what I'm I'm wondering like so
these this is where you would get the
list of things that you want to restrict,
right?
Right.
Gotcha.
Thanks.
Yep.
OK.
So,
So what I want to to get into now is just
the the different kinds of kind of
personas that we would think about
wanting in in our in our development
effort.
I'm calling these Greenfield chat modes,
but they're they're actually now would be
called.
Agents and and these are these are just a
limited set.
You could create as many of these as you
want,
but they some of the ones that we would
take advantage of here.
It would be a project manager,
solution architect.
All of these are valid.
Agents that we would like to be able to
to to find you know what tools they have
available,
whether what are the capabilities,
what are the commands that they can
execute.
You know cause one of the one of the one
of the primary capabilities of a chat of
an agent would be.
You know the ability to make it easier to
actually execute, you know, pre-canned,
pre-canned prompts through those those
command capabilities.
And so if we were to look at what these
individual.
You know,
personas might be able to do so a product
manager,
the skills that they would bring to the
we'd want to bring to the the want them
to have would be things like requirements
translation to be able to convert
business needs into technical prompts.
Contact management be able to maintain
conversation threads for complex feature
discussions, documentation reviews,
stakeholder communication and iterative
refinement,
and their responsibilities would be a
requirement validation, quality assurance,
cross-functional alignment,
risk assessment.
Delivery tracking.
So is that compare that with a a solution
architect which is more focused on being
able to frame complex system design
questions,
validate AI suggested architectural
patterns.
Technology evaluation,
scalability analysis,
integration planning, design validation,
technical governance. So all of these are,
you know,
skills and responsibilities that you
would expect a solution architect to have
and.
What we're really, I think,
doing here in a sense is is building on a
definition of what a solution
architecture architect is and what they
would do. Senior developer.
Here you can see that it's, you know,
more focused on things like what were
related to the code itself.
So if you're you're, you know,
working in trying to improve a piece of
code or write a piece of code,
then this would be the persona that would
be used.
For for doing up.
A technical writer.
So documentation and updating a
documentation we would bring in the
technical writer agent to help us do that
work.
Looking for a a security from a security
review perspective that you know we would
do threat modeling and compliance
analysis and risk assessment.
And then the DevOps engineer is all about
infrastructure as code and CICD pipelines
and expertise related to that.
And the dev test engineer focused on test
case development and management
responsible for you know,
quality metrics and bug triage.
And finally a a site reliability engineer
which is dealing with the incident
response and and SLA, SLA monitoring,
capacity planning and et cetera.
So when you're thinking in terms of your
infrastructure.
Architecture and you're thinking in terms
of you know responding to an incident
this this persona would could be helpful
in doing some of that.
So any questions on just a general what
would go into these individual these
kinds of chat modes?
Or agents sounded.
And then for example,
if you were dealing with this the the the
solution architect agent,
you could have a a whole series of of
prompts here that the agent can execute
that do do do specific.
Things and anything from a comprehensive
system architecture designs to
architectural risk assessment, compliance,
validation,
etcetera could all be prompts which would
be say like if you wanted to do a.
A performance analysis.
You could use this, you know,
activate the solution architect and then
execute the the command associated with
the running the security architecture
prompt and that make it makes it very
easy to.
Basically set up the AI to understand
what the real focus of the work is and
then have it execute that prompt under
that agent definition as the context in
which it's operating that prompt.
Yeah.
Yeah, Dan.
So that those would be like uh commands
in the agent mark and he would.
Yeah, yeah, you would.
You would have a command and what you
would do is then.
Refer to the the prompts.
By having a reference to the the prompt
using an at sign in front of the name of
the file.
So you could have a architecture design
command in the description of the
solution architect.
And then you would have it.
Execute,
just call out to run this at our
architecture design prompt and then that
would take care of tying the two together.
So now with the idea that the solution
architect agent wraps up all this
Yeah.
capabilities.
It makes it easier for you to execute
those prompts,
and if you design your prompts in such a
way that you can pass in parameters,
you can actually have that prompt do more
focused things or provide information.
To the to the prompt that it can use as a
part of its execution.
Hey, is there uh,
there was an example of this and you know.
There's lots of props that are in there.
I'll we can build an example that calls
out to something because we're going to
need to to build up to build an agent and
and see if we can get it to to function.
So if you said something like this is
also a capability if you have a command.
If you say design an an architecture for
a Windows desktop application that
manages a real time inventory for a
warehouse,
the agent would then deliver a component
breakdown, a tech stack,
put patterns that it would.
That it would like to implement
performance angles,
some security design and and and a
rollout plan for actually building it and
putting it into production.
All right,
we we so now let's get into talking a bit
about requirements.
So the so we we but before we get into
actually building that we I just wanted
to bring up the concept of these core.
Instruction files because we would want
to include these.
In in any project that we're working
working with and this is these are good
targets for for something like an
organization wide.
Instruction files.
So you would have to go into the admin
interface for your organization for
copilot and then add these the contents
of these instruction files into the
organization instruction files and then
that they would be available to you.
Whenever you're working in, in, in,
in Copilot in a repository that's in
GitHub.
So that basically, yeah,
so so the idea would be that you by
defining those organization wide,
you wouldn't have to worry about having
to copy them from a a repository or set
up any kind of synchronization mechanism.
You can it's much much easier for you to
put them in the order, right?
But this is the first place we want to
start.
I would would the chat mode now be called
agent dash file instructions or does it
Yeah, yeah, yeah, the chat mode one,
I would rename it to which is a change
really matter?
that I need to to go back and make to is
to go through the the the slides and the
instructions and everything and making
sure everything is oriented towards.
Agents instead of instead of chat modes.
OK. So once we have that established,
then we can start to talk about practical
requirements and if you go to.
Wikipedia and you and you do a a search
for a software requirements.
It'll be you'll you'll find a huge list
of ways that that you can define define
requirements.
I'm kind of gonna focus on 4 different
aspects of this,
which is the the business rules,
the workflows,
the technical stack and the architecture.
All of these are different stakeholders
that are interested in in this the first.
The first the the business rules and
workloads are are the the core things
that would be coming from a from a a a
business analyst and we can use an AI
persona to help us with it with defining.
Those business rules and workflows,
the tech stack would come from an
architecture and the and the architecture
would come more from the technical side
of things.
But these are all aspects of requirements
that we want to be able to capture and
document and then once we've.
Included in in our project definition
then then that becomes something that we
can leverage inside of the A I to
actually make a reference to say I want
to make sure that the we're enforcing
these business rules and once we define
what those business rules are the A I
will then.
Respect them and and and try to implement
them for us.
So, all right.
So the first thing in terms of
requirements that I want to talk about is
some of the business rules.
And so this is a an idea that I had that
I've been working on iteratively to try
to build.
Build out or to prove out a concept that
I think is useful.
I've been using this kind of a model for
a long time and I find it very powerful
for expressing complex business rules.
And one of the the the one of the reasons
I say so is that it can not only be
referenced in a diagram in such a that
you're looking at here,
but it can also be translated into text.
Which actually has the exact same meaning.
So you can actually go bidirectionally
from text into a diagram or a diagram
into a text anytime that you want.
So let me show you some aspects of this
diagram that I think are particularly
interesting.
Let's start that we have an.
I can see here a core entity in this
diagram is an academic and that academic
is referred to by a by an employee number
and that.
That there is a type of academic which is
a teacher and another type of academic
who is a professor and then a third type
of academic which is a teaching professor
which is basically that has the same
capabilities as both.
A teacher and a professor.
So this is where we're modeling
especially multiple inheritance here.
So what's so conceptually we it's very
easy to think in terms of multiple
inheritance.
It's something that you know things are
always.
Can tend to be more than one thing.
They can be have aspects of of multiple
things and so that's an interesting
conceptual design. And then we then it,
but it can be easily translated into a
more of a logical implementation and then
to a physical implementation where.
If it if it doesn't support the concept
of multiple inheritance,
it just uses implementations that can
support that concept.
So here's some other simple things like
an academic is tenured.
So once an academic,
so that's basically they're either tenure
or they're not tenured and this is
referred to as a unary fact.
It's just has a a essentially a binary
value and an academic is also is
contracted until a date.
So you can kind of get a sense of how to
read these and the the idea is that
there's a constraint here which all the
purple things are constraints that says
that an academic is is contracted on only
one date and.
Then there is a a constraint here,
which is an exclusion constraint that
says that if an academic is tenured,
then we don't need to record the the fact
that they have a contract team because
they're not under contract,
they're tenured and they're a salary.
Employee. So that's an interesting thing.
Sarah has another constraint called a.
Uh.
A subset constraint and what this is
telling us is that it's that an academic
has an employee name and an academic
works for a department.
And so that so we're basically saying
that if they work for a department,
they must have an employee name.
Here we have a fact.
This is a professor heads a department
and an academic that works for that
department.
So that if you're an academic that works
for a.
That heads of department.
You must work for that same department
and um.
Here's an equality constraint that says
that a room is has a room number and a
room is in a building,
and the combination of the two of those
things is what identifies that particular
room.
So that a room number and building is the
identifying constraint for that.
So this is some just ideas of of what? Oh,
and one other thing I should show is
here's this attorney constraint.
There's three entities involved in it,
and it says that an academic obtained a
degree from a university.
And that the academic and the degree are
are unique for that academic,
which means that you can't get the same
degree.
You can't get more than that same degree
from another user university in this
model.
And the final constraint I want to show
is this ring constraint.
And this is interesting in the sense that
a teacher audits another teacher and the
ring constraint says that that is.
A cyclical,
which means that a teacher can't audit
themselves or or and so that basically is
saying that you know,
putting a constraint on how a teacher is
able to record that they're auditing.
But.
So just in terms of how this will work,
the the interesting about conceptual
models and there's more than one
modelling approach that uses the the idea
of starting at a conceptual level.
Is that it's it's completely technology
agnostic and and and it can be
transformed into multiple logical models,
which means that I could use this model
definition to produce a database
structure or database schema or a or a
class.
A set of class definitions or class
diagrams or I could use the instead of a
normalized database schema,
I could produce a a data warehouse type
of schema.
It's just a matter of how you interpret
the.
The conceptual model and you can also use
it to to generate UI that that's fairly
sophisticated because you can if you look
at the concept of saying oh well I'm
interested in a a room you can you can
see that that.
For that room,
you would want to know who are the
academics that are assigned to that room
or and then what is the.
So you would see here a list of academics.
You can envision that.
You can also envision that that room
would have a room number.
Field as well as a building field and
potentially the the name of the building
itself,
so that you can essentially infer from a
conceptual model multiple different ways
in which that model can be represented in
or.
Turned into a logical and physical
implementations.
So some of the the things that were
they're useful, it's very it's clear,
it's it's very expressive,
it's it's formal.
But but conceptual model is not a
requirement for what we're working doing
doing.
I'm showing you this because I find it as
being a a really strong way of expressing
the business rules and since I can
produce a a text version of this.
Um.
I It's also easily consumable by by AI.
And this is a object role model is the
notation that I was showing you.
It's a it's a type of conceptual model.
It's supported in Visual Studio by an
extension called Norma. As I mentioned,
these are both textual and visual,
so the text can be visualized and the
diagrams can be verbalized.
And that textual representation is a
formal natural language that can be
validated by subject matter experts,
and they, which is also a very nice thing,
is that you can actually verbalize a
portion of the model,
hand it to a subject matter expert,
and because it's expressible as text,
it can be then easily.
Understood by a subject matter expert and
they can tell you if it's correct or not.
The other I think important when we
thought when I mentioned it as a form of
natural language,
it's actually based on a, you know,
predicate logic and and and.
And there's been, you know,
formal mathematical proofs that you can,
you know, translate,
transform different aspects of a model
into different forms. And it's provable,
so.
I have a a repository where I'm I have a
a definition of this model or in tech
that we can take a look at and I'll show
you that in a second because we can and
if you look at this particular repository
in in GitHub.
I'm basically using it as a series of
blog posts on Greenfield development that
walk us through all of the processes.
The first post in this series was all
about, you know,
using the conceptual model to define
business rules and then.
It moves on from there.
We'll cover some of this material,
but we'll be doing it with a different
problem domain.
So this allows us to it's the the model
that I was showing is based on a a a
white paper where the model was described.
The reason that I'm using it in this
example is because it's already a pretty
well defined domain and we can move
quickly from requirements to
implementation.
Here's the URL for that if you want to
take a look at it.
And it's the third iteration I'm working
on on this particular technique that goes
through and uses a conceptual model to
start the whole development.
All the process.
All right. Any questions on on this?
All right.
So use cases are specific scenarios that
guide data capture.
So we all I think all familiar with them
to a certain degree we you know so you
can do things like you can look at this
model and you can say the conceptually.
If a a person is a a a lecturer,
they can be promoted to a senior lecturer
or a senior lecturer lecturer could be
promoted to become a associate professor.
These are all valid.
Use cases within this particular problem
domain, and so you can do something,
you know,
a use case like adding a new academic to
the faculty and capturing all that
information related to that academic
that's that we need in order to onboard a
new academic.
All right,
before we get into generating a a
business requirements,
let's take a look at trying to create a a
a product manager, a chat mode or agent.
All right,
so let's change into our project.
He will make a new project.
Yes, here you can.
Let me open up a folder.
Yeah.
I think the first one I want to show is.
This project here.
All right,
so I wanted to basically just show you
the models.
That I created as a part of this.
So here we have um.
The actual ORM model itself,
which is a big XML diagram which is
interpreted by the.
Visual Studio and here is the an empty
file that supports it,
but the the actual business rules are
captured here and we can see that it's a
very detailed.
Description of that verbal model and we
can see things like we can use examples
in the model.
We can define different facts that are
that are associated with it.
And this will be this makes a makes a
good a good input into the the AI because
it gives the gives the AI a great deal of
context about the problem domain that
you're trying to solve.
And that's our that's our real goal here
is to give it as much context as this can.
And I'm using the conceptual model
because I can easily create a.
Diagram and produce this level of detail.
The other kinds of.
Models. Yes, Stefan.
Steven.
My apologies,
I might have missed up somewhere in there.
So did you create the ORM model as a
graphic and then had some translate it to
the text there the TXT file?
Yeah, yeah, if I open a Visual Studio,
I can show you that model in in um.
In the diagram form inside of the inside
of the editor editor.
So let me open up Visual Studio.
And let me bring it down into.
Well, we can see it.
And here you can see the the model itself.
And then there's um.
We want to pick up the tool.
So this this is on Visual Studio,
not not not code correct.
This is not code.
There's no extension for this in code.
You need Visual Studio to to do this kind
of work.
And.
I'm looking for.
Uh, there's a.
So here's the here's the model.
We can then select the model and in the
I'll bring up the orbiterum Twitter we
can do look at the the the the browse
that model and we can also bring up the
fertilizer.
So here's the verbalization browser and
you can select that any area in that
model and you can see that the the text
version of that and that can be saved.
Which extension is this? I'm sorry,
which extension is this?
I opened it up in Visual Studio,
but it just opened up the the text.
Yeah, yeah, you have to install that tool.
It's it's called enorma NORMA.
OK. Is it, it's an extension, right?
Yeah, but yeah, I think you have to.
I think to you know if you search for it,
you'll you'll find that extension,
install it and you should be able to do
what I'm doing here with this model.
Norma NORMA, correct?
Correct.
So anyway, so this is the model.
This is how we produce that verbalization.
This is basically just say I wanna
verbalize the whole model and you can see
that here.
And then I I I'm able to use that now the
text version of that in a Visual Studio
code to define.
Define that that set of business rules.
Now the other thing I think is
interesting is that these.
These actual these for the sake of this,
what I'm trying to say is that I used a I
actually to look at the to look at the
business rules and generate a list of of
workflows or or use cases.
Based on what it's what it understands
about the domain that that I've given it
and it was able to produce a a reasonable
list.
Now you probably wouldn't do that for
your own projects because you would you
would use a business analyst to do that
but.
This is just one way that I did.
I thought it was interesting that I could
derive these directly from the OR model
and then I use a a prompt to convert
these into detailed use cases that.
That describe the what the different
functionality should be within the
application itself.
All right, so that's this project.
Any other questions on the the conceptual
side of things 1st and what I did there?
Could you just show it in Visual Studio
again?
So let me open.
Because when I opened it up it looked a
lot smaller. I'm on the Part 5 branch.
I think.
I think I closed it. Let me open it again.
But.
Yeah, yeah,
that one's a smaller model that I'm using.
What I found when I was going through the
process the first,
the first and second time is that the the
size of the model was was was taking a a
a long time to iterate and I want.
So what I wanted to do was to take a
smaller model.
And push that model all the way through
to.
An implementation just to get the process
worked out,
properly get the instruction file set up
correctly.
OK.
Right.
And so I used a smaller model for that
and they're looking at actually a version
that's a little bit older than what I had
had put into the the 3D version of it.
But yeah,
that was that's that was the plan.
This is the model I'm working towards
implementing and.
I'm I'm finding this to be a a really
interesting process because of you know
the you know in terms of basically saying
if I have the business rules I can
produce a a the the.
Working applications just based on the
based on those business rules that
enforce those rules and uh allow you
essentially create a user interface.
An API level player and a back end layer
that this that allows me to implement the
application.
So, so there's that.
So let me open another folder we'll get
into.
Our Um.
That's here.
And.
Let's go with to.
Our project folder.
So what I would so yeah.
So the first thing I think we should do
is it's work on creating a.
An agent.
2.
Need to put that out for that product for
that product owner persona.
So let's first thing I want to do is
rename this to.
Actually,
I think it needs to be under copilot.
And then we would create a.
And then we can go down.
To our configure custom agents since I
wanna create a new agents.
And then that we'll call that new agent.
Now the product manager.
Oh no, I product.
Post it.
So I want to.
All right, so.
Because no.
Your file name is a equal sign.
Does that matter?
Yeah, that matters.
All right,
so there's the shell and then we want to
be able to add.
Some, some, some, some behaviour,
some capabilities as any specific
instructions that we have for.
Uh, for a product manager, so uh.
So you're gonna go to even to AI,
so you know what are.
Uh, typical.
OK, behaviors.
Not any.
Product manager.
So in a prompt first approach,
we just have a prompt.
That would produce a a number of
different.
A different behaviors that it's capable
of doing and then so we can then say then
add.
Please.
Behaviors.
Yeah.
Roduct Manager agents.
Alright, so there's that.
So it's gonna go through and create that.
So the other things that we can do is say,
OK, well let's let's figure out,
find out what the capabilities are and.
Here we can see that it's it's changed
the description,
it's changed what the tools that it's
capable of doing,
and it's dropped the boilerplate message.
Uh, so the description now is uh,
let's go ahead and.
Let's keep it.
And we can now look at the what's going
on.
I lost my key by me. All right,
so let's go ahead and preview the file.
Open the preview and then you can see
here that.
We have some core behaviors that it
sounds like and listed.
And it says that it's an operational
guide.
With analyzing features requirements with
prioritizing some example use cases for
this,
some constraints and some boundaries and
some successive indication.
Applicators.
Oh, so that's.
Interesting. All right.
So we have to talk about capabilities.
So that was some typical.
You could go to this.
So here's communication capabilities,
technical capabilities.
And then we could add these capabilities
to this.
And now got to the Um.
To the agent.
Again,
we're using AI to start the process.
This wouldn't be the the the finish of
defining an agent like this. You know,
we would review this and you know,
pair up anything that we think is not
actually relevant or applicable that
we're trying to accomplish and review the
things that are.
Remaining and make sure that they're they
they're accurate and reflect how we want
this agent to behave.
And now we see core capabilities added.
And.
Um.
Let's look up to the.
Uh um.
Uh, that would be skills.
So it's come up with the a couple
querying data.
Platforms, analytic skills,
communication skills.
So treat.
Right,
so we probably don't need the customer
facing skills.
Another way that we could define this is
a.
Add.
A custom agent.
To the prompts.
And see what it produces here.
Planning domain skills and notice it
didn't include customer interaction.
And we could add these then to our.
To the agent and then the the last things
we wanna be able to add is.
Commands and or identify prompts.
Alright,
so it's thinking about this and um.
And in terms of making the modifications
to our agents.
Any questions while this is thinking?
Well, just a comment.
I was doing the same prompts and it was
way different,
like not very verbose at all.
30 years.
Yeah.
That's interesting 'cause I was noticing
how similar my results were to what John
was getting.
Right. So there could be something.
Um.
Yeah 'cause I do have some of my own user
settings that.
Add some additional flavors to this that
might be might be impacting us.
That's something in my I I would just say.
I wonder if I can get to that from here.
I don't see it so I could, I could.
I'll dig it up and I'll show it to you.
I have to find the the folder light that
it ends up putting these things in.
So this isn't so this is good.
And then let's add this to.
To uh add the I would say uh what are the?
Oh.
Cranes.
And.
So.
So here it's creating some research
commands,
some documentation writing commands.
Collaboration commands,
some validation and quality.
You know,
now it's it's starting to figure out what
we're what we're trying to do.
Um.
So we'll go ahead and say yes,
but we want to add those to the agent.
And now that we have this agent,
is it on our list?
Yeah, so I see now we have the uh.
The product manager.
agent that we now can select and and
utilize.
All right, questions.
So I think um.
What we've created here is something a
little bit redundant,
and I think there's a lot of things that
are mentioned in different sections that
may be.
Conflicting.
Or not conflicting,
but at least redundant.
So we it might be better for us to.
Yeah,
I have this prompt where we would ask it
to create a create an agent that had the
typical capabilities behaviors.
Skills, et cetera. And um.
Oh, what I wanna do now is a um.
Oh.
Means.
Which demands?
I need it.
Could use the profile.
So the idea what I'm trying to get to
with a prop like this is you know.
If there's something that's more
sophisticated than just executing a
single command.
We can actually get.
Profile the capture that particular that
particular command in much more detail
and then have that reference inside the
inside of the the the persona inside of
the agent and then the agent will then be
able to.
Execute those.
As prompts and so it's identified 15
different prompt files.
That it it it thinks it would be a good
idea to create.
And let's we have to do to create.
How about just?
The the the product requirements one.
So.
Uh, and that is gonna be a prompt.
Oh.
And now it should go ahead and um.
Build a profile for us that.
That'll create this new file called a.
It's going to be create dash PRD prompts
dot MD.
So we should see a new file show up for
that and we'll be able to see what it
thinks that we need to to do for that.
And just notice that the reasons why it
thinks that these are.
These are good prompt files are that it
it's reusable so that we can perform that
that that that specific that capability
over and over.
It's it the prompt files ensure a
standard consistent quality and format
and so we.
Get some ability to have a familiar for
all of the profiles.
It allows us to accept inputs like the
feature, the epic,
the scope of the the requirements,
the complexity.
It's complex enough to need the guidance,
but but common enough to to templatize.
And then it also can encapsulate some
product manager best practices into the
the process structure.
It doesn't think it can create that file.
But it has that.
It is.
We'd like you to play the full text here
so you can click file manually.
Let's go ahead and do #1.
Uh,
not sure why it wasn't able to create the
file since it was able to create the
other files, but.
We can do that ourselves with the go
ahead into our prompt folder.
Let's create a new file.
Which is the.
Let's see, what was the name of the file?
Let's see that.
I.
Uh.
PRD.
What?
And then.
And then go ahead and just insert that
text into the file.
So here now we have a create product
requirements.
A document requirements document that
completely defines the product being
specified.
And then what the problem statement is,
these are the inputs,
what the target users are,
the business goals,
the current context and what the scope is.
And then create a structured product
requirement file that includes all of
these aspects, which is executive summary,
a problem definition.
Etcetera.
And then what the output format should
look like and then what it goes through
and describes how to build each of these
sections.
After those sections it it gets into this
11/12/13 of them 13 and then we have a
change log and some references at the end.
So that's.
That's good. What I want to do next is.
Look out.
Product Manager.
And look at the Um.
I'm gonna look for here. Is it?
Is it actually room create dash PRD?
And then we see no results.
So what we want to do is update the.
The agent.
Well, let's see what it does with that.
So it's gonna update the.
Said file editing is currently disabled.
Oh, you know what I bet it is?
I bet the the product manager's not
allowed to modify file create files maybe.
You see here the tools don't specify edit.
We saw, we saw the the agent working at.
And actually, you know,
controlling what what we're able to
actually do. So that was interesting.
All right, so it's doing a replacement.
There we see PRD creation.
And here are done.
Relatively of.
Prompt file and is that the only main
down here available prompt files?
And then it's coming soon.
It wants us to create these other ones.
It's, I think, interesting.
And that looks like the change there and
another change here with all that and at
the top.
Um, keep those changes.
We also need to to add.
Now prompt.
Files.
Another deal.
And the profiles metadata.
What it does is it basically makes
available to the agent the ability to to
call out a specific profiles.
And here we can see about referencing
that profile at the top.
Sounds might be a change in how edits,
how the agents work.
So I guess we don't need this.
Yeah,
in chat mode based agents there is a
profiles,
but there's that looks like they've taken
it out of the agent schema.
All right, this is cool.
Any any questions on this?
I think we've built out a pretty robust.
Agent here with the property manager and
we we should be able to execute then some
OK.
of the commands that are associated with
it.
OK, well.
Oh,
what was the command you did to update
the tools?
Like I I just put the prompt add prompt
files metadata.
It didn't update the tools.
I yeah yeah I I actually had edited the
file manually and just it it suggested
Did you just say?
these as two things I should add and
that's what I did.
So it was it was basically this I added
this particular part if I went in here
and had a comma.
You can see that it's suggesting execute
and edit.
I added the execute one so that it would
be able to, you know,
run commands in the terminal.
I needed to.
Oh.
We could also add in instructions if we
want directly here that says that the the
the agent is only able to.
Edit files in the you know the the
requirements folder or something else
like that so that we can basically kind
of keep the concept of not being able to
edit things,
but only allowing editing within a
particular folder structure.
It might be a a good thing for safety
purposes.
Alright,
so the next the next steps I wanna do is
basically let's create a.
Um.
Let let's create a a requirements
document for for the the calculator
application that we started out with
earlier in in the course where we
actually, you know, built it kind of.
Manually by hand using AI assistance.
Now we want to try to do something that's
a little bit more structured,
a little bit more engineered.
And here we're going to take advantage of
a product manager chat mode to do to do
this. So we can say here create.
Requirements.
Document.
Or maybe.
web-based.
Calculator.
But the doc and the.
And.
Requirements.
Folder.
And this will work because it because the
I I will understand.
And then be able to infer a.
You what what the what the requirements
are from its knowledge of and that
therefore we should be able to get a a
pretty decent requirements document from
it. But if you had,
you know if you had went in and and did
something similar to.
What I had done was to find a document
that contained the business rules and
text and and what the expected workflows
that you wanted to try to implement.
You you would do a decent job of actually
creating requirements from that that you
could use as the basis of a a
requirements document that.
That you could actually use to help use
AI to help you generate some output for.
OK.
Alright,
so it's going through and creating use
cases now.
So and with the successor criteria for
those use cases,
homework problem verification use case
shopping budget calculation.
Ever recovery and learning.
Complex nested expressions.
Yes.
And propose a solution with some core
architecture pieces.
And so that that's kind of an interesting
thing. It was that we once we have that,
you know,
the product manager is not necessarily an
expert in technology.
We can then have a solution architect
review the proposed architecture and make
recommendations.
For that, and you could actually,
you know,
extract that into more of a technical
requirements document that you could also
utilize.
All right,
so it's still going through and creating
some of the user stories.
And so now they're getting down into
actually actual input implementation
level instructions that we're that are
guiding the implementation.
All right,
so we're almost ready for our break.
Over the break,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
switch over to the Greenfield branch and
I'll move some of this,
these agents and our instruction files
over onto that branch and I'll bring over
our requirements document.
And then we'll go on to the next topic,
which is.
I wanna I wanna I wanna align this with
something called vertical vertical slices.
Because I've what I've been finding is
that when I'm generating, you know,
larger projects like this,
it's a is a instead of writing the
individual tiers one at a time,
we would maybe start with the database
tier and then build out a schema and
maybe pop.
Populate it with some test data and then
build a an API layer on top of that that
can talk to the database and then build a
user interface on top of that that can
talk to the API.
What I found in terms of just working
with generating you know a larger larger
corpus of of code.
It takes a long time to go through that
whole process in order you can get to a
point where you can actually see
something that you can manipulate and use
and evaluate.
I kind of have to bake the whole cake in
order for you to be able to actually see
if it tastes good.
And instead a vertical slice would say
break this up.
This project implementation plan into
individual vertical slices,
which means that you're going to
implement a piece of the application all
the way from the the user interface.
All the way through to the back end,
and so it won't contain the full
functionality,
but it will contain enough functionality
for you actually to demonstrate something
to a user.
You can get some buy offs in terms of
whether you're headed in the right
direction.
And so I find that organizing
implementation plans around circle
slicing is really useful.
And what's interesting is that you can
utilize your business requirements to say,
OK, take a look at these.
Business rules these these workflows that
you intend to support and break those
down into vertical slices so that they
can be they can be deployed.
And then another interesting benefit of a
vertical slice is that.
Some of them actually can be implemented
in in parallel.
So you can you want to establish the core
functionality of the application and the
underlying infrastructure to support it.
You can then say, OK,
I want you to build out this feature and
this feature and this feature in
different sessions and they can all work
together.
Together to build up functionality very,
very, very, very quickly.
So we'll we'll take a look at that after
break and then and so I I'll,
I'll have a brand,
I'll have all you'll be able to pull down
the Greenfield branch and then you'll be
able to do.
We'll be able to talk about that,
so I'll see you guys in an hour.
Thanks.
Thanks, John. Bye.